LIZETH VERA

206-910-2126 | lizeth.veraro@gmail.com

2717 western avenue, 432 | Seattle Washington - 98121

Summary

Financial analyst with more than 5 years of experience in diversified manufacturing and service industries, experience with accounting processes and financial reporting to create more efficient and cost effective solutions.

Expertise with planning, budgets, accounting, account analysis, inventory control, management reporting, financial reporting, forecasting, and standard costs.

Skills

// Financial strategic planning, prepare budget and forecasts, review of budgets vs. actual to ensure accuracy.

// The ability to manage peers, teams and processes.

// Strong Microsoft Excel ,Word and SAP skills.

// Basic HTML - CSS and JavaScript, Visual Studio and GitHub.

Education and training

University of Washington | Seattle - currently Full stack web developer (MERN).

Galvanize | Seattle - December 2018 | 6,5 Hours Javascript Fundamentals Mini Bootcamp 1.

Code Fellows | Seattle - November 2018 | 15 Hours Code 102: Intro to JavaScript.

Code Fellows | Seattle - October 2018 | 8 hours. Code 101: Intro to Software Development & Careers in Tech

National Learning Service SENA | Colombia 2008

Associate of Applied Science: Accounting and Finance.

Experience

Junior Financial Controller | Eficiencia y servicios S.A | Medellin - Colombia | May 2017 - Sep 2018

- → Founder of the Economic Control area and leader of 3 employees
- → Reduce of indirect spending through financial analysis, consumption reduction and contracting activities. Managed and developed of 3 employees.
- → Define and implemented business programs and contracting strategies that reduced indirect spending resulting in over \$150 million Colombian pesos annual cost savings.
- → Implement controls and procedures for risk mitigation for procurement processes.

- → problem solve throughout the day helping with school homework or a more serious child-related crisis.
- → Hand in hand with this is potty training.
- → Teach the kids a culture and new ways of doing things, rules and consequences.

Manufacturing Cost Analyst | Creative Colors S.A | Bogotá - Colombia | Aug 2014 - Mar 2016

- → Build strong partnerships within finance and operations to ensure timely and accurate cost data, including related product cost analysis and inventory account reconciliations.
- → Identify and support continual process and procedure improvements.
- → Assist with the budgeting and forecasting process. Make recommendations on level of detail in each process.
- → Analyze financial statements and income statements to review the company's financial performance.

Manufacturing Cost Supervisor | Henkel Colombiana S.A | Bogotá - Colombia | Feb 2013 - Apr 2014

- → Develop daily tracking reports of manufacturing labor hours by department, product and supervisor.
- → Forecast annual and long range profitability and conducted break-even analysis for new projects.
- → Perform periodic audits of costs, identified cost trends and initiated corrective measures as required.
- → Provide financial support for contract negotiations and evaluated profit impact of new business.

SAP Master Data Analyst | Henkel Colombiana S.A | Bogotá - Colombia | Sep 2011 - Jan 2013

- → deletion, and enhance master data content in SAP for the client's business division, ensuring integrity and accuracy as required and on call availability.
- → Generate and analyze inventory reports; make decisions and solve problems to optimize inventory based on cost and service level.
- → Provide direction to global manufacturers and suppliers on dates and quantities needed for scheduling production to meet customer demands.
- → Identify severe inventory or capacity conditions that will adversely affect customer satisfaction and communicate to management; make recommendations for solution.

Supply Chain Analyst | Henkel Colombiana S.A | Bogotá - Colombia | Aug 2009 - Aug 2011

- → Execute the purchasing of finished goods and component materials from global manufacturers and suppliers based on the requirements of the organization.
- → Negotiate with suppliers on the status of purchase orders, expediting, deferring or canceling orders when necessary, and ensuring proper inventory levels to fulfill customer demands.
- → Provide direction to global manufacturers and suppliers on dates and quantities needed for scheduling production to meet customer demands.

- → Identify severe inventory or capacity conditions that will adversely affect customer satisfaction and communicate to management; make recommendations for solution.
- → Maintain strong working relationships with internal and external customers, especially those that may impact the Supply Chain function and effectiveness.

Cost Control Assistant | Henkel Colombiana S.A | Bogotá - Colombia | Jan 2009 Aug 2009

- → Develop processes for monitoring unit cost variances.
- → Analyze inventory valuations.
- → Perform the month-end cost accounting close.
- → Interact with team leads on an ongoing basis regarding their budgets and variances.
- → Manage inventory budget and corporate inventory planning as it relates to cash flow.